Robert F. Harrison fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Robert F. Harrison fonds
[196-] - 1984
F-46
Q100146414
88 cm of textual records 36 photographs ca. 150 architectural drawings
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION: 18 photographs located in F-46-1-0-0-3 PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION: 13 photographs located in F-46-3-1-0-14 PHYISCAL DESCRIPTION: 5 photographs located in F-46-3-1-0-31
Harrison, Robert F.
Robert F. Harrison is one of the key contributors to the architecture of Simon Fraser University. His firm was responsible for designing and building the WAC Bennett library according to design specifications outlined by Erickson and Massey (the architects responsible for the overall design of the university). Harrison's firm also designed and built the Academic Services building, and made later alterations to it and to other buildings on campus.
Robert Harrison was born in Vancouver in 1925. He became a registered architect in 1954, and became the Registrar of the Architectural Institute of British Columbia in 1961. Later, Harrison was made Chair of the Institute's Examining Board (circa 1964). In 1963 Harrison submitted an entry to the contest to design the new university that would be built on top of Burnaby Mountain. His design finished 4th place. According to the contest parameters, the top five winners would each be given a contract to build a section of the campus according to the winner's overall design. Harrison took Erickson and Massey's basic outline for the library, and expanded it to reflect his own ideas. After the first phase of building, Harrison designed a new administration building in keeping with the architectural character of the university. He also made alterations to the Academic Quadrangle, designed later additions to the library, and made alterations to other buildings at Simon Fraser University.
published
Full
Revised
Title of fonds based on its provenance.
Fonds consists of records reflecting Robert F. Harrison's contributions to the architecture of Simon Fraser University. Records reflect the architectural competition to design the university, and include plans, construction records, and building specifications. Also includes newspaper clippings, correspondence, reports, information releases, minutes, change orders, test results, inspection reports, notes, tenders, financial records, specifications, addenda, photographs, and architectural drawings.
The materials were arranged by the Archivist.
University Library; Photographic materials; Architectural drawings; Textual records; Buildings and structures
The Robert F. Harrison fonds was donated to the SFU Archives by Robert F. Harrison in 1999.
All accessions have been processed as of February 2006. No further accruals are expected.
Please consult the inventory for the W. Randle Iredale fonds, F-47 and Zoltan Kiss fonds, F-48.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
Series descriptions and file lists are available.
- SFU architectural competition records, 1963; F-46-1; 4 cm of textual records 18 photographs; Physical description: 18 photographs located in F-46-1-0-0-3
  published
  Series consists of records relating to the Simon Fraser University architectural competition. The contest was held in 1963 to choose the overall design for the new university. Includes newspaper clippings, correspondence, reports, information releases, minutes of meetings with Gordon Shrum (SFU Chancellor), and photographs of the proposed site.
  - University competition, 1963; F-46-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 46-1)
    Textual records
    Open
  - Minutes - Chancellor, 1963; F-46-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 46-1)
  - Proposed university site - Burnaby mountain (photographs), 1963; F-46-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 46-1)
    Textual records; Photographic materials
- SFU architectural plans, [196-] - 1984; F-46-2; 1 cm of textual records ca. 150 architectural drawings; Container No 8 located at 30-2-3-1
  Series consists of architectural drawings and plans for work done at Simon Fraser University by Robert Harrison. Includes plans and drawings for different phases of library construction and plans for other buildings at Simon Fraser University.
  Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
  - SFU library plans, [196-] - 1984; F-46-2-1; 1 cm of textual records; Container No 8 located at 30-2-3-1
    - P-1 conceptual view of library (2 copies), 1963; F-46-2-1-0-1 (Other - irregular 46-8)
      Pending review
    - Library A-1 to A-26, revisions A-27, 28, 29, 1964; F-46-2-1-0-2 (Other - irregular 46-8)
    - Library F-1 to F-18 schedule and revisions, 1964; F-46-2-1-0-3 (Other - irregular 46-8)
    - Library A-1, A-8, F-1c, F-3c, F-1b, F-2b, F-2c, F-3b, 1964; F-46-2-1-0-4 (Other - irregular 46-8)
    - Library addition, 1975; F-46-2-1-0-5 (Other - irregular 46-8)
    - Alterations to Book Sorting room, 1980; F-46-2-1-0-6 (Other - irregular 46-8)
    - Library building - Bookstore alterations, 1982; F-46-2-1-0-7 (Other - irregular 46-8)
    - Library alterations to First floor, 1984; F-46-2-1-0-8 (Other - irregular 46-8)
    - Library colour drawing, [196-]; F-46-2-1-0-9
  - Other SFU building plans, 1970 - 1982; F-46-2-2; Container No 8 located at 30-2-3-1
    - Academic Services - index A-1 to A-15, 1970; F-46-2-2-0-1 (Other - irregular 46-8)
    - Academic Services - A-25 to A-34, 1970; F-46-2-2-0-2 (Other - irregular 46-8)
    - Academic Services building, 1975; F-46-2-2-0-3 (Other - irregular 46-8)
    - Administration building alterations, 2nd and 3rd floors, 1982; F-46-2-2-0-4 (Other - irregular 46-8)
- SFU construction records, 1963 - 1981; F-46-3; 57 cm of textual records 18 photographs; Physical description: 13 photographs located in F-46-3-1-0-14 Physical description: 5 photographs located in F-46-3-1-0-31
  Series consists of records relating to the construction of the library and other buildings at Simon Fraser University. Records reflect the different stages of construction such as site excavation, concrete tests, electrical work, and millwork furnishings. Includes correspondence, change orders, test results, inspection reports, notes, correspondence, minutes of job meetings, tenders, and financial records.
  - SFU Library construction records - Phase 1 and 2, 1963 - 1968; F-46-3-1; 45 cm of textual records
    - Architects representative - R.N. Sinclair, 1964 - 1965; F-46-3-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 46-1)
    - Architects representative - R.N. Sinclair, 1965 - 1967; F-46-3-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 46-1)
    - Change orders, 1965 - 1966; F-46-3-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 46-1)
    - Change orders approved, 1964 - 1966; F-46-3-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 46-1)
    - Change orders pending, 1964 - 1965; F-46-3-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 46-1)
    - Concrete, 1964 - 1965; F-46-3-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 46-1)
    - Concrete tests, 1964 - 1965; F-46-3-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 46-2)
    - Construction notes, 1963 - 1966; F-46-3-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 46-2)
    - Correspondence - Erickson-Massey, 1963 - 1966; F-46-3-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 46-2)
    - Correspondence - general, 1964 - 1965; F-46-3-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 46-2)
    - Correspondence - general, 1965 - 1966; F-46-3-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 46-2)
    - Electrical, 1964 - 1965; F-46-3-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 46-2)
    - Excavation, 1964; F-46-3-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 46-2)
    - Excavation notes (13 photographs), 1964; F-46-3-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 46-2)
    - Hardware, 1964; F-46-3-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 46-2)
    - Inspection, 1965 - 1966; F-46-3-1-0-16 (Archival box - standard 46-2)
    - Job meetings, 1964 - 1965; F-46-3-1-0-17 (Archival box - standard 46-3)
    - Learning resources area, 1966 - 1967; F-46-3-1-0-18 (Archival box - standard 46-3)
    - Millwork furnishings, 1965 - 1966; F-46-3-1-0-19 (Archival box - standard 46-3)
    - Phase 2, D.W. Thompson and Co. Ltd., 1966 - 1968; F-46-3-1-0-20 (Archival box - standard 46-3)
    - Plastering, 1964; F-46-3-1-0-21 (Archival box - standard 46-3)
    - Program references, 1963 - 1966; F-46-3-1-0-22 (Archival box - standard 46-3)
    - Progress payments, 1964 - 1965; F-46-3-1-0-23 (Archival box - standard 46-3)
    - Ptarmigan Constructors 1/2, 1964 - 1965; F-46-3-1-0-24 (Archival box - standard 46-3)
    - Ptarmigan Constructors 2/2, 1964 - 1965; F-46-3-1-0-25 (Archival box - standard 46-4)
    - Reinforcing steel, 1964; F-46-3-1-0-26 (Archival box - standard 46-4)
    - Revisions requested by contractor, 1964 - 1965; F-46-3-1-0-27 (Archival box - standard 46-4)
    - Schedules, 1964; F-46-3-1-0-28 (Archival box - standard 46-4)
    - Site meetings progress reports - Phase 1, 1966; F-46-3-1-0-29 (Archival box - standard 46-4)
    - Structural - Choukales, Woodburn and McKenzie, 1963 - 1965; F-46-3-1-0-30 (Archival box - standard 46-4)
    - Study carrels (5 photographs), 1964 - 1966; F-46-3-1-0-31 (Archival box - standard 46-4)
    - Study carrels - Phase 2, 1966; F-46-3-1-0-32 (Archival box - standard 46-4)
    - Surveys, 1964; F-46-3-1-0-33 (Archival box - standard 46-4)
    - Tenders, 1964; F-46-3-1-0-34 (Archival box - standard 46-4)
    - Weekly reports, 1964 - 1965; F-46-3-1-0-35 (Archival box - standard 46-4)
    - Windows, 1964 - 1965; F-46-3-1-0-36 (Archival box - standard 46-4)
  - SFU Library construction records - later additions, 1975 - 1981; F-46-3-2; 9 cm of textual records
    - Addition - change orders and claims, 1975 - 1976; F-46-3-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 46-4)
    - Addition - contemplated change orders, 1975 - 1976; F-46-3-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 46-4)
    - Addition - correspondence, 1977 - 1981; F-46-3-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 46-5)
    - Computer room and alterations - contemplated change orders, 1977; F-46-3-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 46-5)
    - First floor, 1977 - 1978; F-46-3-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 46-5)
    - Seventh floor - change orders and claims, 1975 - 1977; F-46-3-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 46-5)
    - Seventh floor - contemplated change orders, 1976; F-46-3-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 46-5)
  - Other SFU building construction records, 1966 - 1971; F-46-3-3; 3 cm of textual records
    - Academic services, 1970 - 1971; F-46-3-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 46-5)
    - Oil storage tank, 1966 - 1970; F-46-3-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 46-5)
- SFU building specifications, 1964 - 1984; F-46-4; 28 cm of textual records
  Series consists of detailed descriptions of dimensions, materials, and costs for construction of the library and other buildings at SFU. Includes architectural, electrical and mechanical specifications, addenda, and supplementary general conditions.
  - SFU Library specifications, 1964 - 1984; F-46-4-1; 14 cm of textual records
    - Specification: Library building 1/2, 1964; F-46-4-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 46-5)
    - Specification: Library building 2/2, 1964; F-46-4-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 46-5)
    - Architectural specifications: Phase No. 2 - completion of Fifth floor, 1966; F-46-4-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 46-6)
    - Mechanical specifications: Phase No. 2 - completion of Fifth floor, 1966; F-46-4-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 46-6)
    - Architectural specifications: completion of Learning Resources area - First floor, 1966; F-46-4-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 46-6)
    - Mechanical specifications: Learning Resources area - First floor, 1966; F-46-4-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 46-6)
    - Addition - architectural specifications, 1975; F-46-4-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 46-6)
    - Addition: complete addenda, 1975; F-46-4-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 46-6)
    - Addition: contractors bids, 1975; F-46-4-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 46-6)
    - Addition: mechanical services specifications:, 1975; F-46-4-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 46-6)
    - Architectural specifications: alterations to Book Sorting room, 1980; F-46-4-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 46-6)
    - Architectural specifications: alterations to Book Store, 1982; F-46-4-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 46-6)
    - Architectural specifications: first floor alterations, 1984; F-46-4-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 46-6)
    - Amendments and supplementary general conditions, F-46-4-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 46-6)
  - Other SFU building specifications, 1966 - 1982; F-46-4-2; 15 cm of textual records
    - Structural and architectural specifications - Boiler House addition, 1966; F-46-4-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 46-6)
    - Soil Investigation: proposed Academic Services building, 1969; F-46-4-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 46-6)
    - Architectural specifications: Academic Services building, 1970; F-46-4-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 46-7)
    - Addenda: Academic Services building, 1970; F-46-4-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 46-7)
    - Heating, ventilating, plumbing, and drainage specification: Academic Services building, 1970; F-46-4-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 46-7)
    - Architectural specifications: Academic Quadrangle alterations to AQ 3146-8, 1980; F-46-4-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 46-7)
    - Architectural specifications: Administration building - Computing Science alterations, 1978; F-46-4-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 46-7)
    - Architectural specifications: Administration building - Computing Centre alterations, 1981; F-46-4-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 46-7)
    - Administration building - Computing Centre alterations -- Architectural Addendum No. 1, 1981; F-46-4-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 46-7)
    - Administration building - Computing Centre alterations -- electrical specifications, 1981; F-46-4-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 46-7)
    - Administration building - Computing Centre alterations -- Electrical Addendum No. 1, 1981; F-46-4-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 46-7)
    - Administration building - Computing Centre alterations -- mechanical specifications, 1981; F-46-4-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 46-7)
    - Administration building - Computing Centre alterations -- Mechanical Addendum No. 1, 1981; F-46-4-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 46-7)
    - Architectural specifications: Administration building - Second floor alterations, 1982; F-46-4-2-0-14 (Archival box - standard 46-7)
    - Architectural specifications: Administration building - Third floor alterations, 1982; F-46-4-2-0-15 (Archival box - standard 46-7)